cabi.org 2019-10-29

# Privacy policy - CABI.org

This Privacy Policy (the “Privacy Policy”) explains how we collect, use, share and protect your personal information (“Information”). The information shall be used in accordance with the permissions granted by you and in accordance with the UK Data Protection Act 2018 and EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). If we update this policy, we will post any changes on our website.This Privacy Policy is also intended to assist you in making informed decisions when using our Websites. Please take a minute to read and understand it and please note that it should be read in conjunction with our General [**Terms and Conditions**](https://www.cabi.org/terms-and-conditions/) and our [**Cookie Policy**.](https://www.cabi.org/cookie-information/)

CABI cannot be held responsible for the content or the privacy policies of external websites to which we may link.

## Who are we?

CABI (“CABI”, “we”, “us” or “our”), CAB International, trading as CABI and recognised in the UK as an International Organisation as defined by the UK International Organizations Act 1968 and formalised by Statutory Instrument 1982 No. 1071 and having its main administrative offices at Nosworthy Way, Wallingford, Oxfordshire, OX10 8DE, UK, is committed to protecting your privacy.

## What is your personal data?

Personal data relates to a living individual who can be identified from that data. Identification can be by the information alone or in conjunction with any other information in the Data Controller’s possession or likely to come into such possession.

## What information is being collected?

You may send us or we may ask you for the following information:

  * your full name
  * your date of birth
  * your contact information such as your address and postcode, your email address, telephone number, mobile telephone number, fax number
  * institutional affiliation
  * credit or debit card information, information about your bank account number and sort code or other banking information
  * general information about yourself such as professional interests, your experience of our services and products or other services and products and your contact preferences
  * your contact with us such as a note of a call, an email or letter you send to us or other records of any contact you have with us
  * your browsing information (which includes information about the Websites, Applications and other CABI Products  and Services you visit, any searches you may undertake, your location or location for search purposes in respect of your use of certain products and services)
  * In the event that you apply for a job with CABI, we will require further professional information about yourself by way of a job application or your Curriculum Vitae

**CABI may also collect certain information about your hardware and software, this includes:**

  * your IP address
  * browser type
  * operating system
  * access times
  * referring website addresses

## Who is collecting it?

CABI is the data controller (“Data Controller”) for the purposes of the Act and can be contacted at Nosworthy Way, Wallingford, Oxfordshire, OX10 8DE, UK or at [ **dataprotection@cabi.org**](mailto:dataprotection@cabi.org).

## How is it collected and used?

**We can get your personal information when you:**

  * buy a product or service from us (including buying products online or over the phone)
  * register for a specific product or service
  * subscribe to newsletters, alerts or other services from us
  * ask us for more information about a product or service, or contact us with a question or a complaint
  * take part in a competition, prize draw or survey
  * take part in user testing
  * visit or browse our Websites, Applications and other CABI Products

We may also collect information about you from other organisations, if this is appropriate.

We may also collect information about you from other companies, our business, or project partners.

**How will it be used?**

CABI and/or our partners may use your information in the following ways:

  * to provide products and services that you have requested
  * to ensure that the content on our Websites, Applications and other CABI Products is presented in the most effective manner for your and your computer
  * to perform statistical analyses measuring customer interest in various areas of our sites
  * to develop and improve our products and services
  * for our internal record-keeping
  * to contact you to answer any queries you may have
  * to contact you for market research or marketing purposes where you have given us permission to do so
  * to help with marketing, including testimonials for CABI’s Products and services

If you do not wish to receive information from CABI other than that requested or no longer wish to receive marketing material and communications, please contact us at [ **enquiries@cabi.org**](mailto:enquiries@cabi.org).

## Who will it be shared with?

**We may share information about you with:**

  * partners or agents involved in delivering the products and services you have ordered or used
  * partners or agents engaged to perform services for and on behalf of CABI
  * donors, partners or agents involved with development projects and programmes
  * third parties purchasing products and services from CABI
  * pension and payroll providers
  * project partners and donors, and other professional advisers
  * debt collection agencies or other debt recovery organisations
  * law enforcement agencies regulatory organisations, courts, or other public authorities if we have to, or are authorised to by law

#### D **etails of transfers to third country and safeguards**

We may need to transfer your information to CABI centres or partners and agents in countries outside the EEA (European Economic Area). This may happen if our partners and agents are based outside the EEA, or if you use our services and products while visiting countries outside this area.

## Reporting fraud

CABI is committed to ensuring your information is secure. As part of our efforts to protect your information, CABI will never send you emails asking for your personal information or for your registered password (if you are a registered user).

If you do receive such an email or are asked to disclose this information by someone claiming to work for CABI, please report the communication to our Data Protection Officer using the following methods:

  * send an email to ** **[ **dataprotection@cabi.org**](mailto:dataprotection@cabi.org)
  * in writing to the Data Controller at our registered address: CABI, Nosworthy Way, Wallingford, OX10 8DE, UK

## Your privacy rights

You have the right to ask us to provide a copy of the information we hold about you and to have information removed or any inaccurate information about you corrected. You can do this by sending an email to [ **dataprotection@cabi.org**](mailto:dataprotection@cabi.org).

If you no longer want to receive marketing messages from us, please contact our marketing department at [ **enquiries@cabi.org**](mailto:enquiries@cabi.org) and you will be ‘opted-out’.

You can choose to opt out of all marketing communications or to opt out of marketing in one of several ways such as email, SMS, phone or post.

If you would like your information to be removed from our records or if your information requires amending, then we will endeavour to correct, update or remove your information as swiftly as possible. This can be done using the following methods:

  * send an email to ** **[ **dataprotection@cabi.org**](mailto:dataprotection@cabi.org)
  * in writing to the Data Controller at our registered address: CABI, Nosworthy Way, Wallingford, OX10 8DE, UK

Please note that while CABI will endeavour to make the updates as promptly as possible, communications may be sent using the original details until the changes have been processed.

## Our retention of your information

We take all reasonable steps to retain your personal information only for as long as reasonably necessary or as required by law. If you no longer want us to store your information, you may ask for it to be removed from our records. Please note that such removal may prevent us from supplying certain services to you.

## What about cookies?

We use cookies to recognise users after they have registered to use a website or paid for access to a website. On occasion, we permit third parties to place and read cookies on our customers’ browsers, in order to deliver information of relevance to the user.

Cookies will enable our web-sites to recognize the information you have consented to give and use it to present you with custom web pages. So, for example, instead of seeing just a generic welcome page, you might see a welcome page with your name on it. Some features on this site will not function if you do not allow cookies.Click here for a full description of our [**Cookies policy**](https://www.cabi.org/cookie-policy/).
